Alexander Tu Software Engineer

CONTACT DETAILS

- @ k25650727@gmail.com
- +48 532 646 076
- my website

○ github.com/momipochi **in** linkedin.com/in/alexander-tu

PERSONAL INFORMATION

Citizenship: Poland

Languages: **English** (native), **Chinese** (native), **Japanese** (N2), **Polish** (B2)

OPERATING SYSTEMS

Linux, Windows, MacOS

HARD SKILLS

- Python, Go, Rust, C++, Typescript/Javascript, Java, C#
- React, Vue3, Svelte, NestJS, gin-gonic, Spring
- jest, storybook, tanstack-query, junit
- MySql, PostgresSql, Oracle, MSSOL
- Docker
- Latex

SOFT SKILLS

- Problem solving
- Adaptability
- Not afraid of asking questions

Summary

Software Engineer specializing in frontend and/or backend development. Experience with all stages of development cycle from setting up project to testing and maintaining project, up to delivering product to customers. Well-versed in numerous programming languages, fast to adapt and learn new things swiftly.

EXPERIENCE

SOFTWARE ENGINEER at Snowflake

Oct 2022 - May 2023.

Developing new UI components, update/create APIs, project shipment,
 Snowvation hackathon

SOFTWARE ENGINEER at Crowdconsultants

Aug 2023 - Jun 2024.

♦ Creating backend APIs, reusable UI components, Azure DevOps pipeline, refactor legacy code, introduce new technology to improve development

EDUCATION

ENGINEER DEGREE IN COMPUTER SCIENCE. Polish-Japanese Academy of Information Technology.

Oct 2019 - Mar 2023

- \diamond Basic to advanced programming in Java. Algorithms, machine learning and system design.
- REST api projects, machine learning and applications in Java.
- ♦ Thesis: Education platform for medical student from University of Warsaw

PERSONAL PROJECTS

My website - momipochi.github.io/website/

Retro style terminal inspired website. Built using Svelte/Typescript

GO-REALTIME-CHAT - github.com/momipochi/go-realtime-chat

♦ Real-time chat built in Golang and ReactTS. The main focus of this project is to use threading in Golang. I might add more features like persistency in the future.

JAVA-SPRING-MINI-PROJECTT - github.com/momipochi/java-spring-miniproject

♦ REST project in Java spring and ReactTS, with database for persistency.

TAIWAN AMIGO - github.com/momipochi/taiwan_amigo

♦ Real-time voice/video chat social platform. Built from scratch with websocket, Vue3/Typescript/NestJS/Docker container on Azure/Netlify

PHYSICS BOMB - github.com/momipochi/physics_bomb

♦ Physics simulation of multiple dots traveling from point A to point B using linear interpolation. Written in Javascript.

WEB SCRAPER - github.com/momipochi/exh

♦ Webscraper for downloading images into organized albums. Built with Python.

THESIS - project not publicly available

- ♦ Education platform for medical student from University of Warsaw. Built with React/Typescript/C#/MySQL.
- ♦ The platforms allows professors to easily track group and hand out tests/assignments to students. Students receive tests/assignments to improve skill to identify cardiovascular diseases based on the diagrams.